Patrick Mounts

503.679.8657 | patrickmnts@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/patrickmtns Github: www.github.com/patrickmnts

Portfolio: www.patrickmnts.com

Professional Summary

I am a mid-level developer that manages a strong enthusiasm for code, with a healthy work/life balance. Interested in firms that have the ability to support and foster growth both inside and outside from the office.

Technical Experience

Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap & Responsive Designs,

Git, Ruby

Programming Skills: Agile Methods, TDD, Paired Programming, API's, JSON &

XML, OOP

Frameworks: Rails, EmberJS, Padrino, Sinatra, Rack

Professional Experience

Planet Argon - Portland, OR

Application Developer

Full-Stack Ruby on Rails developer managing all aspects of an application's lifecycle.

- Experience configuring hosting solutions involving multiple providers including AWS and Akamai.
- Worked on 15+ applications providing me the ability to become quickly productive in new applications.
- Experience with Javascript frameworks & toolsets including EmberJS.
- Direct client access has fostered productive and professional relationships that best suit the clients particular use-case and their application's unique scenario.
- Self-Driven: Small team structure has provided the opportunity to wear many hats and become a generalist with many skills.
- Experience creating applications from the ground level, as well as working to improve applications long into their lifecycle.

My contributions can be found in applications such as:

www.nikeinc.com, www.converse.com, www.mcmenamins.com, www.opencityfreight.com, oceanscape.aquarium.org, www.pacglobal.com, www.homezada.com, among others...

Portland Code School - Portland, OR

06/2013 - 08/2013

09/2013 - present

Jr. Web Developer

- 3 month intensive course building necessary skills for success as a Junior Developer.
- Practiced Agile methodology utilizing sprints, standups and retrospectives during/after projects.
- Learned to manage team development process utilizing Git version control.

Education

Portland Code School

06/13 - 08/13

Web development

2006 - 2010

University of Oregon

B.S. in Political Science, Minors in Business & Economics